I shot my wife... prove it.
Fracture is a thriller film directed by Gregory Hoblit.
A husband is on trial for the attempted murder of his wife, in what is seemingly an
open/shut case for the ambitious district attorney trying to put him away.
However, there are surprises for both around every corner, and, as a suspenseful game of
cat-and-mouse is played out, each must manipulate and outwit the other.
Theodore Crawford, played by Anthony Hopkins.
William Beachum, played by Ryan Gosling.
Joe Lobruto, played by David Strathairn.
Nikki Gardner, played by Rosamund Pike.
Jennifer Crawford, played by Embeth Davidtz.
Lt. Rob Nunally, played by Billy Burke.
Fracture is a 2007 legal crime psychological thriller film directed by
Gregory Hoblit and written by Daniel Pyne and Glenn Gers.
Starring Anthony Hopkins and Ryan Gosling, it follows a man (Hopkins) who shoots his unfaithful wife
and then engages in a battle of wits with a young assistant district attorney (Gosling).
The supporting cast includes David Strathairn, Rosamund Pike, Embeth
Davidtz, Billy Burke, Cliff Curtis, Fiona Shaw, and Bob Gunton.
Upon its premiere on April 20, 2007, the film received generally positive reviews from critics, who praised its performances
(particularly those of Hopkins and Gosling), style, and tension, though some criticized the plot as implausible.
It was a box office success, earning $92 million against a $10 million budget.
The film explores themes of perfect crime, prosecution, legal thriller.
The tone is intense.